[Music]
And so we thank you Lord and we give you
praise in Jesus name. And everybody said
[Music]
God bless you. You may be seated.
Colossians chapter
1 verse 16 to verse 20
reads, "For in
him all things were
created, things in
heaven, things on
earth, and things under the earth."
Just join hands with your neighbor right
now and just begin to pray for them as
we look into the word. Can you just pray
for them right now? Father, in the name
of Jesus, we pray for our friend here
who is before us who's sitting next to
us. We pray that your presence will rest
upon them. Just pray for them. Pray for
them. Please pray for them. Thank you,
Lord
Jesus. Thank you, Lord Jesus.
I pray Lord that the light of your word
will shine on
them. I pray that the truth of your word
will rest upon them. I pray that you'll
open the eyes of their understanding to
your
truth. I thank you and I honor you in
Jesus name. And everybody said, "Amen."
Amen.
[Music]
For in him all things were created,
things in heaven, things on
earth, visible and invisible, whether
thrones or rulers or authorities or
powers. All things were created through
him and for him. He's talking about
Jesus Christ. Verse 18, it says he is
the head of the body, the church. He is
the beginning, the firstborn from the
dead. Verse
19, for God was
pleased to have all his fullness dwell
in him. Verse 20, and through him to
reconcile to himself all things, whether
things on earth, things in heaven, by
making peace through the blood shed on
the cross.
The theme of our
Passover for the next three days is the
blood that brought us peace. Today,
however, I want to talk about the blood
of
Jesus that
bought your valuable soul.
We note in Colossians
1 verse 20 the second
part it says that Jesus made
peace through the blood shed on the
cross. His blood
flowed to buy freedom for your soul.
I want us as well to look at Matthew
16:26 which reads as
follows. For what does it
profit if a man gain the whole
world and lose his
soul? Or what shall a man
give in exchange for his soul?
I can say without
questions, I believe that you care for
your
soul because usually in a weather like
this one, people don't go to
church. Worse if it's in an open space
like this
one. So I'm convinced as I stand here
that you care for your soul.
Your soul is
valuable. Your soul is
precious. Your
soul is what Jesus died
for when his blood flowed on the
cross. Jesus asks a
question. What shall a man give?
What shall a person
give in exchange for his soul?
He's using language that is very
interesting
because he is using language in those
days where the people of the time
understood that he is
likening the value of the soul to a
person and the exchange of the soul to
the manner in which people used to
invest make
investments and make
exchanges to get monetary
values. We know today in our world that
one of the things we are advised by
financial advisors is to make
investments which is
important which is
valuable. Many investments are there.
You can go into
stocks. You can invest in real
estate. You can have collectible
items. And these days you can invest in
cryptocurrency. How many of you know?
Maybe you're sitting next to somebody
who's got cryptocurrency. Just find out
maybe
cryptocurrency. All of these
investments have to do with what we are
told. You must secure your life. You
must build a financial
security. These have to do with
financial growth and financial security
which is all good in its own
place. And yet I want to remind us this
morning there are certain investments
good as they are. They are not of a
spiritual nature and they cannot do
anything for your
soul. Caring for your
soul, investing for your soul is the
best investment that you can ever make
in your
life. Jesus asked that
question. What will a person give in
exchange for his
soul? That word exchange interesting.
Jesus borrows from the business
transaction of the day where people used
to butter. They would exchange one
valuable thing for another valuable
thing. When you butter is when you trade
and you exchange a commodity for
another. So Jesus is asking what can a
person do to butter or trade for their
soul?
Which means my implication people do
trade with their soul. Jesus is telling
us people sell their soul. People don't
do what's right for their soul. They
allow their soul to be on sale for
something
else. People sell their soul for earthly
riches. People sell their soul for
fame. In 1 Timothy 6:10, we note how
people are warned. Don't spend all the
time investing in natural riches and
neglecting investing in godly
things. People trade their soul. And
Jesus says in Matthew
6, the riches of this world, good as
they are, they are
corruptible. And the riches of this
world, good as they are, when we die, we
leave them all on this earth.
And the riches of this world, good as
they are, they can never buy our way
into
heaven. And so people sell their soul
for riches. Secondly, people sell their
soul for the passing pleasures of
sin in a moment of passion where people
are immersed in sin and their soul gets
destroyed. Others sell their soul for
the convenience of false doctrine.
Others sell their soul simply through
the laziness of not wanting to take a
step towards God even when they have
opportunity to walk towards God. Like
many of you have opportunity this
morning. You've come here, you've been
invited, maybe you've come on your own,
you have an opportunity today to take a
step towards God. But sometimes people
don't do so. They fail to apply
diligence for the benefit of the soul.
But here's the question. What is the
soul? Why is the soul so important? Why
can't it be compared to other things?
Well, the soul according to the Bible is
the inner part of you. Is that part of
you that God created.
In Genesis 2:7, the Bible tells us that
God made man in the likeness of his
image, and he breathed into his nostrils
the breath of life, and man became a
living soul. So your soul is that part
of you that comes from God. Your soul is
that part of you that is
eternal. Your soul is that part of you
that can never be destroyed.
Your soul is that part of you that can
never be satisfied with silver and gold.
Your soul is that part of you that longs
after God. Your soul is that part of you
that hungers after
God. Your soul is that part of you that
can only be satisfied when it connects
with God, the one who gave that soul.
The soul is that part of us that can
never in any way, its unquenchable
desire can never be fulfilled by
anything else. Jesus said in Matthew 4,
"Man shall not live by bread alone, but
by every word that comes from the mouth
of God and therefore your soul, the only
satisfaction it can have is to be
connected with God." And this is why in
this world we may have all that the
world can give us but still feel empty,
restless with no peace in our lives
because our soul has not connected with
God. But even more so our soul is that
eternal part of us. When we die it's our
body that gets buried but our soul lives
on. It either lives on in the presence
of God or it lives on without the
presence of God. And the interesting
thing is the destiny of where your soul
goes at death is determined by the
choice that you make whilst you still
live here on earth. It's not a decision
that you can leave for later. It's not
something that we can do for you once
you have passed. is not something that
we can come to your grave and do for you
is not something we can do on the day
when you are buried. The decision you
made whilst you were still alive, whilst
you could still think, whilst you could
still decide, whilst you could still
yes, you say yes or say no, that
decision whenever you made it is the one
that determines where you go. So your ve
your soul is valuable because it was
created by God. At least 12:7 says one
day our spirits will return to God the
one who made it because our soul is so
valuable. so valuable that for it to be
bought out of sin and rescued out of
sin, it caused the death of the son of
God, Jesus Christ. A soul is so valuable
that Peter says, "We have not been
redeemed through corruptible things like
silver and gold, but we have been
redeemed by the precious blood of the
Lord Jesus Christ." The word redeem
means to buy
back. God bought our soul back. Bought
it back from
destruction. Bought it back from being
lost. Bought it back from being owned by
Satan. And it cost him the blood of our
the Lord Jesus Christ. So our soul is
precious that God didn't spare his son.
For God so loved the world that he gave
his only begotten son. God was willing
to let his son die on the cross. God was
willing to let his son suffer on the
cross. God was willing for blood to flow
from his son. The blood flowed from his
head. Blood flowed from his side. Blood
flowed from his body. Blood flowed from
the hands that were pierced. Blood
flowed from the feet that were pierced.
Blood flowed when he was gushed on the
back 39 times. Blood flowed. It was a
costly payment, a costly account that he
had to pay to pay for your soul because
your soul is precious. In fact, Jesus is
telling us our soul is more valuable
than the whole world. says, "What can a
man give in exchange for his soul? What
will it profit for a man to gain the
whole world and lose his soul?" Oh, he's
telling us all the world with all that
it has cannot compare to the value of
your soul. So, I want to ask you, don't
gamble with your
soul. Don't play around with your soul.
Don't neglect your soul. Make a decision
today for the destiny of your soul
because your soul is
immortal. We see in the Bible how
Jesus would change his
plans and go to a different place just
to meet one person because he cared for
their soul.
We see in John chapter
4 how Jesus went to a place called
Samaria and there he met a
woman whose life wasn't the
best whose life was going in the wrong
way. But when Jesus met her, Jesus did
not condemn
her. Jesus engaged her in
conversation and finally Jesus showed
her the way. You see, God loves you. God
wants to show you the way. You're not
here by mistake. You're not here by
coincidence. You are here because God's
love has drawn you to this place. It's
not because of us. It's not because of
what we do, but because God's love is
towards you today.
Jesus went to speak to this one woman. A
woman who had lost
reputation. A woman who was given all
kinds of names. A woman who was
ostracized from her own community. You
see, God comes to us and moves in our
direction. Even if people think you are
the worst of the worst, God doesn't
count that. There's not enough sin that
you can commit that can turn God's love
away from you. You can't be too evil for
God not to be able to reach you. God
speaks to the people of the time. He
says, "My hand is not sh to save. My ear
can hear your cry." You're here today
and maybe you look at your life. It is
not where God wants it to be. There's
hope for you today. Jesus Christ died
for you and there's hope for you and you
can move in the direction of God and
invite Christ in your life. In Mark
chapter 5, we see Jesus going to a place
called
Gadara. The Bible tells us there was a
man there who was mentally
disturbed. He was so
tormented that they couldn't contain
him. This man, the Bible tells us, night
and day he would walk around in the
tombs taking stones, cutting himself
with stones, bleeding and crying night
and day. This man was under the power of
the evil one. See, Satan is evil. He's a
thief. Satan steals, kills, and
destroys. He will torture a life. He
will destroy your life. He will take
your life and degrade your life. Satan
will cause your life to be total
misery. But Jesus in his great
love after he had preached to thousands
of people got into the
boat, crossed, went to the other side
just to go and see one man. And when
Jesus met this
man, he prayed for this man and
delivered this man. And after this man
was
delivered, he didn't want to walk away
from Jesus, he followed Jesus wherever
Jesus went. And Jesus turned to him and
said, "I've shown mercy on you. Instead
of you following me, go and tell others
the good things that the Lord has done
for
you. See, the Lord is a good Lord. He's
a good God. He does good things. Even if
your life is tormented, you may be bound
by drugs. You may be bound by
alcohol. You may be looking at your life
that's disintegrating, your life that's
falling away. Maybe they've told you
that you are beyond any rescue. Maybe
they've told you there's no hope for
you. I'm here to tell you your soul
matters to God. Your soul is valuable to
God. And Jesus Christ is here today to
change your soul and to make you a
different
person. You can take a step today and
say, "Jesus, here I bring my broken
life. Here I bring my destroyed life. I
come just as I am. You see, God is not
expecting you to change your life in
your own power. You've tried many times,
you failed. You've made many decisions,
you've failed. You've made many
promises, you've failed. You've made
many New Year resolutions, you failed.
But I'm here today to tell you, there is
hope in Jesus Christ.
There is hope in the blood of Jesus
Christ. Jesus who is able to reach out
to you. Jesus who's able to say to you,
"Come as you
are." And
today as we
remember the death of our Lord Jesus
Christ, I want you to know that your
soul can be transformed. Let me close.
understand that your soul is
valuable and all that God wants is for
you to take a
step. Jesus tells a story in Luke
chapter 12, a very sad
story. A man who worked very
hard, worked so hard that he was able to
reap a big
harvest. And after he had this bumper
crop of a big
harvest, after working so
hard, as he went to bed that
night, he said, "I worked so
hard. I've worked so
long. Tonight, I want to
rest. I want to sleep.
I want to
rest so that tomorrow when I wake
up I will be
able to enjoy my
labor and Jesus makes a
statement what this man didn't
know that is that that
evening his soul will be required from
him Even as he tucked himself in
bed, heaven said, "You
fool, you worked long. You worked
hard for earthly
things, but you never prepared for the
destiny of your
soul. Tonight, your soul will be
required of you.
I pray that should never happen to any
of us here
today. I pray that when the day comes
when God will require my soul or your
soul, we will have made
ready. We will have made sure we take
care of our
soul. As I'm about to pray, I want to
call on you today. You're
here. When you look at your life, you
realize it's not pleasing before God.
When you look at your life, it's not
what God wants it to
be. But as you've been listening to
God's word, you realize, you know what?
I haven't given my soul to Jesus Christ.
I haven't made any preparation for the
destiny of my
soul. But he has an opportunity today in
this stadium this morning. You cared
enough about this meeting to come from
your place and be here in this weather.
Why not go a step further and take
another step to say, "I want Jesus
Christ to come into my
heart." I'm going to call on you where
you are. If you want to accept Jesus
today, for him to come into your life
and be your savior and your lord, and
you want to give your soul to the Lord,
I'm going to pray for you. Would you bow
your heads, please, and close your eyes,
everybody?
Right where you are, if you say, "I need
prayer. Would you please pray for me? My
soul needs God. My soul is not where it
ought to be. Would you please pray for
me as I give my life to the Lord?" If
that is you and you need the prayer
right where you are, would you raise
your hand high? Please let me see. Just
raise it high all over the
stadium. Just raise it high all over.
All over. Raise it high. Yes. I want my
soul to be changed. I want my life to be
changed. Just raise your hand right
where you are. I want to pray for you.
Thank you for those hands. God bless
you. God bless you. Can I ask you if you
raise your hand? I want to pray for you.
This is your day. Don't postpone. Don't
leave it to tomorrow. This is your day.
I want to call you from where you are.
Take all your belongings, your Bible,
your bag, your purse, and come from
where you are and walk all the way to
the front of the stage here because I
want to pray for you. Come right now.
Give them a big hand as they come. Come
on. Come on. If you raise your hand.
Come on. Come. Let's pray
together. Come. Let's pray together.
We'll wait for you. Come on. Here they
come. Give them a big hand as they come.
Come on. Come on. Here they come.
[Music]
Come on.
Let your soul be changed today.
[Music]
Make
it amazing.
Hallelujah. Jesus.
[Music]
How you
Ever
give
you a
[Music]
Wake up and die.
When
I
see
I see me Happy
[Music]
Give
it, give
it,
give
me. Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Yeah.
Wow.
Give
her a
[Music]
Everybody give my
[Applause]
I
am you are
just let your God's people rejoice for
all the mighty mighty harvest and
everybody in front. Come on, let's just
thank the Lord
[Applause]
everybody. One
more. And we still have a few more
people coming
in. Just give us one more song, please.
Hallelujah. I think you need to
congratulate them, everybody, please.
Yeah.
[Music]
Hallelujah.
Don't
lose God.
[Music]
Lo truly.
Hallelujah.
[Music]
[Laughter]
Hey shore.
Li.
[Music]
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah. We thank God that today your
souls will be saved in the hands of God.
You know, there's nothing as said as
when it comes to the end of your life,
you realize that everything you worked
for is not going to help you for the
life hereafter. But it's another thing
when you know that no matter what
happens to me, my soul is safe in the
hands of God. We're going to pray for
you and then we're going to take you for
counseling. There are
people very quickly and explain to you
what receiving Christ is about. And when
they are done, please quickly come back
into the service. All right? You come
back as quickly as you can because we
have another session that's coming. All
right? And just to remind
you, even after lunch, we have another
service. Tomorrow we have a youth
service and in the afternoon we have a
recording service. All right, let's pray
for you. All right, let's pray for you.
Can you raise your hands to God and
follow me in this prayer? Heavenly
Father, say it out loud. Heavenly
Father, can the congregation join us,
please? Heavenly Father,
in the name of Jesus,
I come to
you just as I am.
I invite Jesus
Christ to come into my
heart to be the
Savior and the Lord of my
life. Thank you for hearing my
prayer. Thank you for coming into my
heart.
and for making me a child of God
from
today my life is in your
hands in Jesus
name. Amen and amen. Hallelujah. All
right.
Uh going that way. All right. I'm going
to ask you please to turn to your left.
All of you if you can face that way. All
right. Please just
walk. Don't rush or anything. Can you
follow those people? They will direct
you as to where to go. You can all move
please and please come back as quickly
as you are done. God bless you all.
[Music]
[Applause]
Oh my
god. Oh
[Music]
yeah.
Hallelujah. Oh
yes. What do
[Music]
you Oh yeah.
might
just come
[Music]
[Applause]
might He's good.
[Music]
He's
my Oh,
[Music]
My tonight
might
[Music]
just
be hero.
[Music]
You're singing. You're
and
[Music]
you
might hallelujah.
Hallelujah. Yes.
[Music]
Jesus.
Jesus. For the last time. For the last
time. For the last time.
Oh. Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Come. We deserve it. We deserve it.
In the
in the
says, "I know.
[Music]
I want you to
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah. One more time. One more
time.
[Music]
Hallelujah.
Yes.
[Music]
Hallelujah.
What a bumper
harvest. What a bumper harvest.
Our God is
good. Our God is
good. Thank you,
Bishop, for preaching such a powerful
message to us.
Thank you so much. We want to thank our
lords for the mighty work that he has
done. But
now we are going into a most one of the
second from this what has happened
exciting time which is
offering. We are now going to
celebrate what has just happened. This
is this is the most exciting
time of these services, especially this
particular
one because this is a season. We are in
a season of
reflection of what our God has done. the
sacrifice of our Lord as the bishop has
been teaching
us. It is an
opportunity for the for us to
express
gratitude for the finished work of Jesus
Christ. He has finished it. But there
are works that he has accomplished for
us and obtained for
us. And Deuteronomy chapter 16 verse
16 says, "No
one is to appear before the Lord
empty-handed.
All must give as they are able according
to the
blessings given to
them from the Lord our God. Another
scripture says Psalm 116 verse1 17 says
I will sacrifice you a thanksgiving and
call on the name of Jesus Christ.
What about Jonah where he was in the in
the belly of a
fish? What happened to him? Jonah 2
verse 9 says, "But I will I with a voice
of
thanksgiving will sacrifice to you. I
will fulfill what I have vowed.
Salvation is from the
Lord. And our
scripture which is very
exciting and Fab's Psalm 100 verse4 says
we enter his gates with thanksgiving and
his cause with praise.
When we say
praise to God, we are not giving
something to
God. Thank you are two powerful words
that we use when we are in need or when
we are celebrating something. When we
say thank
you, we are making a declaration.
We are making a declaration that we are
not moving from a starting
line but we are from moving from a
finish line. Whatever we do we do it
from the finish line because Jesus
Christ has already obtained everything
for us.
We are
saying oh Lord you finished all the work
of the
cross. We are saying again what thanks
means is you have received the blessing
of the finished work.
We are not giving God something but we
are what we are receiving from
God. What are we receiving? The
blessings of the finished
work. Thank you. We have seen just one
of them as souls were being born
today. Wisdom is one of them. The
prayers that we've been
giving, those are the blessings of Good
Friday because when he bled on the
cross, he obtained all that so that we
can receive.
And on
Sunday, it is going to be the
responsibility of the
church to be
able to
apply and get
everything that God has obtained for us.
So at this time of
offering, we
are giving in appreciation of what our
God has done. Celebrating and
appreciating what God has
done in thanksgiving and
honor. We are giving out whatever
according to what we can
give. And as we do that, we're going to
ask the
ushers to begin to position
themselves and please follow every
instructions of the ushers as we pray.
Father, we thank
you that you have finished it. Mighty
God, you finished it on the cross as the
bishop was preaching. Mighty
God, you obtained all the blessings.
Mighty God, all these blessings. Mighty
God, we receive them by the
act of offering to you, mighty God, we
offer our entire being, mighty God, we
offer our substance, mighty God, in
thanksgiving to you, mighty God, knowing
that we lack nothing from now on, mighty
God, the devil has no power. The devil
has been defeated. We are seated
together with Christ high above.
In the name of Jesus, we give you the
glory. In Jesus name, we may
begin to take the offering in Jesus'
name. Amen. And
amen.
Hallelujah. We bless you, King of Kings,
for there is none like you. We glorify
your holy name for you alone are
Jehovah.
Holy, holy is your name,
Lord. We bless you,
[Music]
Jesus. We thank you for a time to
worship you, oh God.
[Music]
corner. When I'm
God
[Music]
dwell. Oh Jesus.
I Yes, Lord.
[Music]
A cool
way. Give me more.
[Music]
My
name for your name.
All
Baby,
[Music]
Loyal.
Where are
my way?
[Music]
music. What do you want?
Heat.
Heat. Heat. Heat.
[Music]
I know.
I
got I
[Music]
got Oh
Jesus. Yes, Lord.
We bless you. We bless
[Music]
you. Oh
Jesus. When I
wait when I
wait. When I
wait. When I wait.
When
I know I
[Music]
[Applause]
Hallelujah. Isn't the Holy Spirit the
power of the Lord?
sweet smelling
aroma. As we remain
standing, I'm very excited by his today
to have uh among us someone
that we've known for many years. He
accepted Jesus Christ as his personal
savior way back in
1970 under the student Christian
movement of South Africa.
He attended the tertiary education at
the Southern African School of
Theology and has been in full-time
ministry since 1976 to
date. He's married to
Rose. They're blessed with four
children, three girls, one boy, nine
grandchildren. He's also the founder and
preciding bishop of Zoe Bible Church,
which now has 32 branches countrywide.
He's the founder of global restoration
of apostolic and prophetic order
grappo an international fellowship of
pastors and elders and their
churches with a special emphasis of the
return to apostolic order in the church.
He was consecrated as an episcopal head
in 1996, the first of his kind in the
Pentecostal and charismatic churches in
South Africa. And he also got his
apostolic succession in 2003 under the
international bishop's conference. He's
a vicar general of international
bishop's conference in Southern Africa
representing his eminence bishop Dr.
Leroy Bailey Jr. of the United States of
America. He speaks at conventions,
conferences, universities, colleges,
seminars, radio,
television. He was honored by the
Central African Correspondent College on
17th of August 2006 with an honorary
doctorate of divinity.
I want to say as well, Barcelona, to me,
he is a mentor, a leader that I look up
to, someone who has served in our nation
with
integrity, with dignity, has honored the
cross, has stayed faithful to the cross.
Anytime I've asked him to come over and
bless us and speak, he has said yes.
They have a very very busy program right
now during this time. But because of his
love for us, his love for this nation,
he's here with us. And so, ladies and
gentlemen, I'd like us please to put our
hands together and welcome to the podium
a servant of the Lord, Archbishop Glen
Batuana as he comes to minister the
word. Come on,
[Applause]
someone. Thank you, your grace.
Come on, let's give the Lord a big hand
for his grace
[Applause]
[Music]
here.
Hallelujah. Uh please remain standing
and let us all lift our hands above our
heads and give the Lord Jesus Christ a
round of applause. Amen.
[Applause]
God bless you saints. You may be seated
in the presence of the Lord.
We want to say greetings to his
grace, the preciding bishop of grace
bible
church
and bishop
muso. We also want to say greetings
to Muso, Pastor
Ke, all the council of bishops, the
leadership of Grace Bible Church in
their different levels and categories.
Greetings to you this morning in the
name of Jesus Christ our Lord.
Amen. Let me greet each and every one of
you who have come out in such a weather.
You are
great. Grace Bible Church, you are
great. You are powerful
people. No matter what the weather is,
we're just going to be in the presence
of the Lord.
So your grace, it is always an honor to
come and uh share your
pullpit. You and I
know the serious risk of giving somebody
else your pullpit, but thank you for
trusting
me.
Amen. Um
pastor, I thank God for the opportunity
of sharing these few moments with you.
This
is the most important time in the
history of the Christian faith when we
remember and celebrate the death, the
burial, and resurrection of the Lord
Jesus Christ. The Passover feast in the
Bible signifies the head of all the
feasts that the Lord has ever given to
Israel.
Without a Passover, we have no
Christianity. And so without any further
waste of time, I would like to share
with you from the Gospel according to
St. John uh chapter 18 from verse
4-6. The Gospel of John
chapter 18 verse4-6.
Jesus therefore knowing all things that
would come upon him went forward and
said to them, "Whom are you
seeking?" They answered him, "Jesus of
Nazareth." Jesus said to them, "I am
he." And Judas, who was betraying, who
had betrayed him, also stood with them.
Now when he said to them, "I am he,"
they drew back and fell to the ground. I
would like to repeat verse
six. Now when he said to them, "I am
he," they drew back and
fell to the
ground. The title of my talk is um
entitled, "Why did they fall onto the
ground?" We hear that when the Lord
Jesus said to
them, "Who are you looking for?" They
said, "We are looking for Jesus of
Nazareth." He said to them, "I am he."
And the Bible says, as soon as he said
that, they all fell on their backs. They
fell to the ground. My task at this time
is
to let you know why did the people fall
just at a statement that Jesus made.
Shall we pray
please? Father, we thank you for your
word that has been read in the hearing
of your
people. All we ask is that you would
anoint the lips of clay that would speak
your word.
Your word on its own is powerful enough
to change any
situation. And all I'm asking you is for
accuracy of
speech, for wisdom to be able to
deliver, thus says the Lord, to your
people. Bless this lips of clay, oh God,
and let your will be done, and let your
kingdom come, and let your people be
established in the name of Jesus Christ
our Lord. Amen.
Why did Judas and his gangsters who had
come to arrest Jesus fall onto the
ground when the Lord said, "I am he whom
you are looking for."
In today's type of uh
Christianity, the most desired thing
when some of us as men and women of God,
we pray for people is to see them fall
to the
ground. Some do not believe that people
can be healed without falling.
It has become fashionable in these
days that when we pray for people, we
want to see them
falling. It is such a pity that
something so powerful and something so
wonderful that was done by the Lord
Jesus Christ and in many other places in
scripture has now become something that
is in the fashion.
Sometimes you will hear men of God
saying to people when they are standing
in front and they are going to pray for
them because they are sick and then they
say um relax.
You are in the presence of the Lord.
Relax. Relax. Don't resist the
anointing. Don't resist the anointing.
Just relax. You know, and and and then
and then they say, "Close your eyes."
And while whilst you are closing your
eyes, the next thing you hear is a hot
clap on your
face from the anointing of Bishop
Chisam. And how can you not
fall when the whole five-fold ministry
lands on your cheek?
It is
unfortunate we have made the move of the
Holy Spirit to be mechanical. We want
the Holy Spirit to work the way we want
him to
work and that is very very
unfortunate. I'm sure that the story of
Gethsemane is a familiar story with many
of you here.
The Lord Jesus senses that his time has
come to go to the cross and the Bible
says that he took his disciples and he
went with them to the garden of
Gethsemane.
He placed eight of them minus Judas
maybe just outside the garden and he
takes three of them and he steps into
the garden and he positions them in a
certain place and then he himself goes
further to go and pray and the Bible
says he prayed a simple prayer. Father
let this cup pass but let it not be my
will let it be your will. He prayed that
prayer three times and every time he
prayed and stopped, he went to check on
his disciples and find that his
disciples are fast
asleep. After the third
time, the Bible says the Lord said to
them, "Well, you might as well just
continue sleeping
because the enemy is at the door." And
as he said
that comes Judas's carot with his band.
He had soldiers. He had police from the
high priest. He had people that were
wellarmed to the teeth. And this is a
man who had been serving under the Lord
Jesus Christ, an ordained apostle who
had been sent to go out and preach the
gospel. When the Lord Jesus sent them
out two by two, he was part of them. He
was there to heal the sick. He was there
to see the miracles under the authority
of the Lord Jesus Christ. But now he has
turned to be an enemy. It's amazing.
But sometimes we expect the enemy to be
out there, but sometimes the enemy is
right next to us. We're eating with the
enemy. We're working with the enemy.
We're sleeping with the enemy. And there
is no more a deadlier enemy than the one
that is
inside. May God help
us. When the Lord Jesus Christ said to
them, "Who are you looking
for?" And they say, "We are looking for
Jesus of Nazareth." The Bible says they
fell. I just want to highlight that
fact. Why did they
fall? Because we don't hear that the
Lord Jesus
Christ scared
them. He didn't say,
"Ha," and then they
fell. He had no sword with him. He
didn't even take a karate position to
show them that now I'm going to fight
guys. No, he didn't.
He didn't even raise his
hands and make some magic and say
abracadabra you are all going to
fall. Neither did he use any gimmicks
that some of the pastors who are praying
for sick people today are
doing. People will be lining up here to
come for
prayer. And the pastor goes up and down
the stage like a roaring
lion. And he chooses one of them and
fixes his eyes on them. And he says, and
he says, and he says, and that person,
he starts shaking and shaking and
falling down. And I've seen other men of
God, they come to pray for you and when
they come next to you, it's like they
kicking a
football and then the person they did
that that do that to falls
down. It's the in thing today for
pastors to
see that they must fall down.
The Bible tells us
that Jesus said, "I
am." When the Lord Jesus said that
phrase, "I
am," he was actually
invoking the presence of God.
You will remember that one day when
Moses was investigating a burning tree,
a burning
bush, he went there and the first thing
he heard as he was approaching the tree,
the voice said to him, "Moses, do not
come any
closer because the place where you are
standing on is holy ground."
And then the Lord said to him,"I
am the God of your fathers Abraham,
Isaac, and
Jacob." So that word I am or that phrase
I
am describes the very presence of the
presence of
God. So when the Lord Jesus said to this
band of
robbers in
When he said I
am, he invoked the presence of God to
come and very
cool. Nothing that would say he's going
to attack
them. Very cool and collected. He just
said, "Well, if you're looking for
Jesus, I am."
And they fell.
Moses sent by God, he said, "When I go
to
Egypt, when I speak to the elders of
Israel and tell them that the God of
your fathers has sent me to you, whom
shall I say he
is?" And the Lord said to them, he said
to Moses, "I am that I am?"
Please keep that in mind because that
word I am that I am in the Hebrew it it
says I will be there as there I will
be. I will be there. Moses is asking too
much questions. What about this? What
about this? What if this happens? And
God says, don't
worry. Don't worry about what is going
to happen. You go and tell Pharaoh, get
my people out of Egypt. Set them
free. What's the sign? And God says,
don't worry about the sign. I will be
there as there I will
be. That simply means when you obey my
word, I will show
up and I will choose how I show
up. I will choose what instrument to use
when I show up.
So that word I am that I am simply means
that he is a god of
selfexistence,
selfsufficiency and immediate presence.
When Moses reached
Egypt, God had told him to put his rods
down because he made him to practice
whilst he was at the burning
bush and the rods turned into a snake
and God said, "Pick it up and he picked
it up." So he was ready to do that in
Egypt.
So when he went to Egypt and Pharaoh
said, "Who is God? I don't care about
your God. The slaves are mine. I don't
know your God, so I'm not going to
release them." And then Moses took the
rod, put it in front of Pharaoh, and
threw it onto the floor. And the rod
turned into a
snake. Then Moses looked at the eyes of
Pharaoh. Pharaoh called his magicians
and he said, "Boys, let's come and show
this man we know what he is doing. He's
using magic."
And so the magicians of Egypt, they
came, they threw their rods down and
those also turned to be
snakes. And that
part, God did not tell him that that's
what's going to happen.
Only thing he knew is that his rod can
turn into a
snake. But God didn't tell him that when
that happens, they will also take their
rods and they will also turn to be
snakes.
So when Moses saw that I think he and I
know Aaron they looked at each other
what what now we've done our miracle and
they are also equating they equaling our
miracle and then the Bible
says the mo the rod of Moses began to
swallow the snakes of Egypt and that was
God manifesting as I am that I
am. So every
time he uses this phrase to get people's
attention, I am. Then he says who he is.
When God was going to give the ten
commandments to the children of Israel,
they stood there and God spoke to them
and he said, "I am the Lord your God
that brought you out of the land of
Egypt." I am carries the very creative
power and presence of God.
And we use that phrase many times when
we describe ourselves. I am. I am this.
I am not that. I am this. And we are
least aware of the fact that every time
we open our mouths and we say I
am, we are actually creating what we say
we are.
You see, God spoke. Everything came into
existence when there was
nothing. And the Bible says we have been
created in the image and likeness of
God.
So I
am whatever you say after I am you
become.
So if you say I am weak, you have just
created weakness because I am carries
the creative power of almighty
God. If you say to yourself, I am
stupid. I am dumb. I'm good for nothing.
You are going to be all of those things
that you say with your mouth because
that phrase I am invokes the creative
power of almighty
God. So that is why the Bible says we
need to be careful what we say with our
mouths because we will reap the things
that we
say. If parents start telling their
children or giving their children names
from
birth. So when this child grows
and
no is the parents who prophesied
Who's your name? I
am. Who's your name? I am.
So please know and understand this is
the reason why the Lord Jesus came into
the world and he used that phrase many
times when he was addressing the people
to try to make them to understand who he
is that the power of God is resident on
him that's why he said I am the way I am
the truth I am the life and no one comes
unto the father but by me that is who he
[Applause]
is he said, "I am the bread of
life. If you eat me, you will not die.
And if you die, I will resurrect you
because I am the resurrection and the
[Applause]
life." He said, "I am the good
shepherd. I am able to take care of my
sheep and I lay my life down for them. I
am makes you whatever you say after you
pronounce I
am. In the book of
Malachi God says
behold I am
God and I change
not. I change
not. We have many problems in our
world. We have many problems in our
lives. One of the things that we can do
to change
situations is to watch what we
say. Watch what we say. Especially
us, not only do we have the natural
ability to create through our mouths, we
have the power of the Holy Spirit
residing in
us. You ought to be
careful especially
So
today as we going to pray you have
needs stop
saying I am
poor in our family. No one has ever been
rich. Another young man when they were
asking
him what is he doing for a living? He
was talking on one of the well-known
radio stations in our
country. He said, "If it were not for my
parents, I would be
rich. If it were not for my
parents, I would be rich."
In other words, he says, "I am poor
because my parents made me poor. I was
born into a poor
family." Another young man said, "I want
to sue my parents for giving birth to me
without my
permission." These are the crazy things
that we
say and then we expect positive
miracles. If you speak negative, you
will reap negative.
The Bible says whatsoever you say or
whatsoever you sow you will
reap.
Hallelujah. And so
today if there is
nothing that has ever happened in your
life, in your family, in your business,
this is the time. This is the hour for
you to start creating it.
[Applause]
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah. And
so we need to change the way we
speak. The way we
speak. Another lady said to Sir Winston
Churchill, this is many years ago, Sir
Winston
Churchill, you are fat. You must try and
lose
weight. And so Winston Churchill looked
at
her and he said,
"Lady, I may be
fat, but I can do something about
it. You are ugly, and there's nothing
you can do about it.
So what I'm
[Music]
saying that's
why it is when we
confess with our mouths that Jesus
Christ is Lord and believe in our hearts
that God has raised him from the dead.
You
speak what the word of God says for you
to be saved.
So from
today what you see is what you
get. You must
know shame.
Confess the Lord Jesus.
[Applause]
Now, I'm going to
request that situation
on whether it's in your personal
life, in your home, at work, wherever
there is a nasty
situation, you need to confess the word
of God against that situation.
The Bible says, "Greater is he that is
in you than he that is in the world." We
are told we are more than conquerors
through Christ who strengthens
us. These are the things that we are
supposed to confess and speak them.
Any one of you, any one of
you, you can speak to this mountain and
say, "Be removed and be cast into the
sea. And if you don't doubt, it shall be
removed." And then he says, "Whatsoever
you
say, you will
have." So,
Hallelujah.
So that's why I said in the beginning of
my talk, Grace Bible Church, you are a
great people. You are a powerful people.
If you can come out under
Eeveeo, you are great. You are powerful.
Say something that is godly. Say
something that has divinity. Say
something that is
creative. And listen, the Lord Jesus
said we will be held responsible for the
things we say. We will be held
responsible.
Suzandaza I'm not going to make an altar
call ask anybody to come forward but I
am going to say if there is any
infirmity
abnormality in your body you're not
feeling okay you're feeling sick
sometimes you're not physically sick you
are emotionally sick you are
stressed going through depression and
all those kind of things we can pray
today through the name of I am that I am
and command the situation to
change. So if you have a situation that
you need to be changed, I'm going to
request that you stand right where you
are. Please don't come forward. Just
stand. We are going to pray and ask God
to change situations that are in our
lives, in our homes, in our churches. My
God, in our churches, I'm dealing with
the topic in Zoe Bible Church for the
past three weeks now to the fourth one.
The church is sick. One time we invited
his grace, Bishop Sono with two other
gentlemen and they were speaking on the
church is sick and how can the church be
healed? I've gone back to that. But our
churches are sick.
We need to speak and we need to
pray. Must help us in our churches.
Situations must
change. Let's stop hating each other as
Christians. Let's stop as Christians.
Let's stop as Christians. We are
children of God. We need to be positive
with each other. We need to be positive
about our pastors. We need to be
positive about our churches. God what we
say with our mouths we are going to get.
Hallelujah. And so as I pray today
please pray with me. You can pray in
your heart. You can pray out but let's
believe God together. Guy the situation
that you are representing as you are
standing is taking a change this day.
Let us pray.
We
appeal. We appeal
Jehovah. We
appeal. You are
alive. You've been alive and you will be
alive forever.
You have said that we must come boldly
to the throne of
grace to obtain help in the time of need
because next to you we have a great high
priest who has been tested in every way
just like we
are. And you said for that
reason we must come with confidence,
with
boldness. And here we are,
Father. Physical
impossibilities,
abnormalities, malfunctions in our
bodies, sickness and pain and disease.
This day, Father, we speak the healing
that is contained in the name of Jesus.
You said you are the Lord our God that
healeth us.
Every person who is standing for a
sickness in the body in the name of
Jesus
abnormalities to change and be healed in
the name of Jesus Christ of Nazareth.
the mess in which we live in some areas
in the name of Jesus. We pray that you
would give healing in our families, in
our communities in Jesus name. Let the
power of the word of God that is being
preached every day, the power of the
spirit of God transform
Africa in the name of
Jesus. We pray that you would give
wisdom to our leaders and
governments. That they would lead this
nation with
righteousness,
integrity, and with the power of knowing
that you are
[Music]
God. Let your church be healed.
before you come, Lord
Jesus. And most of all, this
day we bring before you our presiding
bishops. Father, we thank you for having
used this man from his youth until now.
You have kept him. You have sustained
him. You have allowed him to go in and
out of this country with safety and
security. You have allowed him to have
men and women who are his sons and
daughters in the ministry. And we are
here today because he has said yes to
the calling of God upon his life. Cover
him, protect him, my God, provide for
him, raise unto him faithful, diligent
sons and daughters who are going to
stand with him and lift up his hands
when he gets
tired and give him a good and a healthy
life, length of days, longevity, oh God.
Let it be his portion in the name of
Jesus. Keep him until your purpose is
fulfilled in his life.
We bless all the leadership of this
church and glorify you for what you are
doing with them and through them in this
country and beyond this country. All of
this we pray and believe that you have
heard us and answered us in the name of
Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen and amen.
Everybody say I
am. I
am. In the name of Jesus, keep I am. God
bless you.
[Music]
Heaven in the
in the
[Music]
of
Bless
the mighty
[Music]
Say with me, I'm a child of God. I am a
child of God. Say it loud. I am a child
of God.
I am born again.
God is my father. God is my father. I
have the name of Jesus.
Which is powerful.
I speak in that name.
I command it not
name. I'm healed by the stripes of
Jesus. I am
redeemed, set free from all kinds of
bondages. I don't walk in
fear. I walk in
faith. I'm a child of
God. I am born
again. I'm full of the power of the Holy
Spirit.
I have
authority in the name of
Jesus to break down principalities and
powers. If you believe that, give the
Lord a big hand of praise because that's
who you
are. That's our shout.
Hallelujah. Bless the
Lord. Well, we just want to thank the
Lord for Archbishop Botswana and he came
here. He has a a service going. So,
Bazala, let's just show our appreciation
for the servant of the Lord.
Amen. Let's take our seats just for a
short
while. I'm so grateful, Basel. We are
very much on time today. And so we're
going to have a a break
uh from now
until uh
2:30 for you to go and have something to
eat, refresh yourself. But look at your
neighbor and
say you don't go. But just a few
reminders before we go in a
break. Our second service starts at
1430. That's half past 2 on the
dot. We are doing the seven
words. We have our
bishops, senior
administrators and overseers who will be
preaching. So come and that's going to
be our last service for today.
Please be aware that if you have lost
and found items, take them to the
information desk that's located near the
main
entrance.
Tomorrow it's t-shirt and denim day.
[Music]
So all the Grace Bible Church branded
t-shirts, we wear them tomorrow and our
denims and
uh we are now as we close. I'm not sure
if
it don't have an
item. We don't have an item. Are we good
here? Okay. All right. So, we're going
to close in a word of prayer and then is
is that the way? Okay. Am I Am I
right? Oh. Uhhuh. Oh, music group. They
say the music group is going to lead us
as we close in prayer. Do I close first?
They lead us first. They lead us first.
I pray after and show. Father, we want
to thank you for the service as we take
a break and come back at 2:30 for
another service. We thank you for
telling us about our soul and even
teaching us about I am as we are
continuing to have services. Thank you
for empowering us and blessing us in
Jesus name we pray. And everybody
said God bless you. We'll see you at
half past 2. Hallelujah.
[Music]